koenigsegg.com 2019-08-18

# Privacy Policy - Koenigsegg

**1\. GENERAL**

1.1 This privacy policy (”Privacy Policy”), describes how Koenigsegg Automotive AB, with its principal place of business at Kelliehousevägen 73, Valhall Park, 262 74 Ängelholm, Sweden (“Koenigsegg”), collects, uses, discloses, stores and otherwise process personal data.

1.2 We respect your right to privacy, and we are committed to comply with applicable data protection rules and to safeguard your rights. We want to make sure that you are aware of what types of information we collect or obtain from you via the website (https://dev.koenigsegg.com) how this information is used and how we protect it.

1.3 This Privacy Policy describes, amongst other things, which information we collect about you, how your personal data is processed and for what purposes we collect and use the personal data. This Privacy Policy also describes your rights and how you can contact us about the use of your personal data.

1.4 Koenigsegg is the data controller responsible for processing your personal data in accordance with applicable data protection legislation.

**2\. WHAT TYPES OF DATA DO WE PROCESS?**

2.1 Personal data means all types of information which can, directly or indirectly, be used to identify a living physical person (“Personal Data”).

2.2 Koenigsegg collects and processes personal data about you when you visit our website, including:  
(i) information about how you in particular use our website and service; and  
(ii) technical data, which may include your URL, IP address, unique device ID, network and computer performance, browser type, language and identifying information, general geographical location and operating system.

2.3 Koenigsegg further collects information if you comment on a story on our website, including contact information (such as name, email address and personal website URL, if applicable).

2.4 Information about how we store and use cookies is described in our cookie policy, available at https://dev.koenigsegg.com/cookie-policy/

2.5 Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

_Analytics_

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

Google Analytics (Google LLC)  
Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google LLC (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

_Contacting the User_

**Contact form** (this Application)  
By filling in the contact form with their Data, the User authorizes this Application to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.  
Personal Data collected: email address, first name, last name.

**Comment form** (this Application)  
When leaving a comment on this website, the User’s name, email address and website (optional) are added to a database of commenters. This list is not used for any purpose other than as a site archive. A commenter will not be contacted as a matter of course, but may be contacted if a question raised by their comment requires follow-up.  
Personal Data collected: email address, name and website (optional).

**Managing contacts and sending messages**  
This type of service makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User. These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC.)  
MailChimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC.  
Personal Data collected: email address, first name and last name.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. Privacy Shield participant.

**3\. WHY DO WE PROCESS YOUR DATA?**

3.1 Koenigsegg collects personal data relating to you for the following reasons:  
(i) to ensure the efficient technical functioning of the website;  
(ii) to analyse your use of the website in order for us to develop and improve the website;  
(iii) to contact you with, for example, newsletters that you have requested and to respond to communications you have sent us;  
(iv) to fulfil requirements by law.

**4 THE LEGAL GROUNDS FOR PROCESSING PERSONAL DATA**

4.1 Koenigsegg’s processing of your personal data is based on certain legal grounds. These legal grounds are described below.

_Legitimate interests_

4.2 The legal basis for processing personal data such as technical data when you browse the Koenigsegg website is that the processing is necessary for the purpose of the legitimate interests of Koenigsegg. The legitimate interest of Koenigsegg is described further above in section 3.

_Performance of a contract_

4.3 Koenigsegg processes your personal data in situations where it is necessary for the performance of a contract with you. For example if you purchase our products or if you make inquiries about such products.

_Consent_

4.4 Koenigsegg’s processing of your personal data is based on your consent where you provide us with your email address by signing up to our newsletter on our website. You can at any time withdraw your consent to such processing either by clicking the unsubscribe link in our newsletter or by contacting us. For contact details see section 9 below.

_Legal obligation_

4.5 Koenigsegg may process your personal data for the purpose of complying with safety standards and other statutory requirements, based on the legal ground that this is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which Koenigsegg is subject.

**5\. FOR HOW LONG DO WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA?**

5.1 Your personal data is stored only for as long as there is a need to keep the data in order to fulfil the purposes for which the data was collected in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

5.2 The Personal Data will be deleted if:  
1\. the purpose of collection and use of personal data has been achieved; or  
2\. you withdraw your consent (if applicable) to the collection of personal data by contacting us (for contact information, please see Section 9 below).

**6 HOW MAY THE DATA BE SHARED?**

6.1 Koenigsegg will not sell, trade or lease your personal data to third parties. However, Koenigsegg may share personal data with trusted subcontractors in order to provide you with our services. They may need access to the personal data in their assignment for us, but they will not be allowed to use the personal data for any other purpose.

6.2 Unless otherwise set forth in any specific information regarding our processing of your personal data, Koenigsegg will not transfer your personal data to any country outside the EU/EEA.

6.3 Personal data may be disclosed by Koenigsegg to comply with legal requirements or other requirements from official authorities, in order to safeguard Koenigsegg’s legal interests or to detect, prevent, or draw attention to frauds or other safety or technical problems.

**7\. PROTECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

7.1 You should always feel secure when you provide your personal data to us. We have employed a wide range of security measures to help protect your personal data against undue access, modification and deletion.

7.2 We protect your personal data using commercially reasonable safeguards to prevent loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. These measures include data encryption, firewalls, automatic timeouts and one-time access links that expire within hours. Therefore, you can rest assure that your personal data is in safe hands.

**8\. YOUR RIGHTS**

_Corrections, additions_  
8.1 You are always entitled to access your personal data for viewing, and to request that we correct or update your personal data.

_Restriction of use and data portability_  
8.2 Under certain circumstances (expressed in applicable data protection legislation), you may request that Koenigsegg restricts the use of your personal data or delete your personal data. If you have provided us with personal data, you also have the right to have your personal data resubmitted to you, in a structured and accessible format, for transfer to another user/processor.

_Requests and Complaints_  
8.3 If you wish to exercise any of the abovementioned rights or if you have any questions regarding personal data held by us or this online privacy policy, please do not hesitate to contact us (for contact information, please see section 9 below).

8.4 Should you be dissatisfied with our processing of your personal data, please let us know, and we will do our best to met your complaints. Your integrity is very important to us, and we always strive to protect and secure your personal data in the best possible way. Should we nevertheless, in your opinion, fail in this ambition, please note that you are also entitled to lodge a complaint with the Swedish Data Protection Authority (Sw. [Datainspektionen](https://www.datainspektionen.se/)), or such other authority as may be determined in the future.

**9\. HOW TO CONTACT US**

You can contact us at: Koenigsegg Automotive AB, Kelliehousevägen 73, Valhall Park, 262 74 Ängelholm, Sweden, or at our email: info@koenigsegg.com.
